菲尔 非常感谢你来帮忙
Phil, thank you so much for helping,
尤其是在昨天晚上杰对你那么无礼后
especially after Jay was so rude to you last night.
我想开始一项新的家庭传统
I wanted to start a new family tradition.
某种程度上来说 我成功了
In a way, I succeeded --
现在我们有了不喜欢菲尔日
we now have Phil Un-appreciation Day.
请听啊 请听啊
Hear ye, hear ye!
别这样
Nope.
我宣布首届
I hereby declare the opening
年度邓菲运动会开始
of the first annual Dunphy Games.
坚决不要
Hard pass.
力量的考验 运气的测试
Tests of strength, games of chance --
冠军将获得大家梦寐以求的邓菲圣杯
with the champion receiving the coveted Dunphy chalice
和这张酸奶乐园的礼品券
and this gift card to Yogurtland.
菲尔 没人要玩啦
Phil, it's not going to happen.
你的反对我已经听到了 大长老
Your dissent has been noted, town elder,
但也许应该让年轻的人们
but perhaps those who've seen fewer winters
来投一票
should cast a vote.
谁敢接受面条比武的挑战
Who dares accept the challenge of a noodle-joust?
没人买账 老爸
No sale, Dad.
好吧 你尽力了 儿子
Oh, well. Nice try, Son.
我还是开车原路返回佛罗里达吧
I'll probably just drive back to Florida, then.
很高兴见到各位
Great to see you guys.
我就是觉得每个人都长大了
I just thought with everyone growing up,
一项新传统也许能给我们一个
a new tradition might give us another excuse
每年聚一次的理由
to get together every year.
亲爱的 我们今天就可以聚在一起
Oh, baby, we can get together today
去参加乔的足球队派对啊
for Joe's soccer-team party.
有超级英雄要来
We have superheroes coming.
有超人 X战警
We have the Superman, the X-Men.
杰就这么叫我和我爸 傻X战警[前男人]
That's what Jay called my dad and me. Ex-men.
好疼
Ohh! That hurts!
-怎么了 怎么回事 -没事
- Why, what happened? - ?Oh, it's nothing.
可能是我踩高跷伤的屁股又犯了
It's probably just my stilter's hip flaring up.
不 好像不是
No, it's not.
你看起来不太好啊
Oh, you don't look that good.
你发烧了吗
Do you have a fever?
不知道 我感觉不出来
I don't know. I can't tell.
糟糕 你在烧呢
Ay, no, you're burning up!
您好 我订了你们的超软胶底袜子
Hi, I ordered your Ultra-Soft Gel-Heel Socks,
两只袜子都标着"L"
and they are both marked "L."
"L"是指左...[left]
And "L" is for --
'L'指的是大[large]啊 好好笑
"L" is for large. Hilarious.
我以为我穿着两只左脚的袜子呢
I'm thinking I've been wearing two left socks.
我好可爱
I am adorable.
能稍等我一下吗
Can you hang on a second?
-你好 -克莱尔 一切都好
- Hello? - Claire, everything is okay,
但我现在在带菲尔去医院
but I am taking Phil to the hospital.
他死了
He's dead!
我只是在闭目养神啦
I was just resting my eyes!
-天啊 怎么了 -没事的 亲爱的
- Oh, God! What happened?! - It's okay, honey.
我就是有点胃疼
I just have a little bit of stomach pain.
坚持住 亲爱的 我我我 我这就过去
Hang in there, sweetie. I'll -- I'm -- I'm -- I'm coming.
我 我马上 我马上过去
I'll be -- I'll be -- I'll be there.
你不是吧 兄弟
Really, Schwartzy?
我要推杆的时候给我打电话
Calling me while I'm putting?
就是这种下三滥的手段 你老婆才会抛弃你
It's bush-league moves like that why your wife left you,
我们才会打扑克却从不邀请你 我们才...
why we still play poker and never invite you, why we --
是歌洛莉亚
Oh, it's Gloria.
杰 去接乔 然后到医院找我
Jay, pick up Joe and meet me at the hospital!
怎么了 是斯黛拉出事了吗
What happened? Is it Stella?!
不是 是菲尔
No, it's Phil!
等下 我接另一个电话
Wait a minute, I'm -- I'm getting another call.
-老爸 -我听说了
- Dad-- ?- I heard.
好了 海莉和卢克在你那个俱乐部上班
Okay, Haley and Luke are working at the club.
你能带上他俩 然后到医院找我吗
Can you grab them and meet me at the hospital?
当然 抱歉 各位
Sure thing. Sorry, guys.
情况紧急 我要把车开走了
Emergency, I gotta take the cart.
-什么 -俱乐部会所离这里45米呢
- What?! - ?The clubhouse is 50 yards away.
先走23米 然后扎营休息
Walk the first 25, make camp,
明天早上再走完剩下的
and then tackle the rest in the morning.
别管乔了 我让米奇和小卡去带他
Forget about Joe, I'll have Mitch and Cam bring him.
菲尔 多疼啊 打分1到...
Phil, how's the pain? On a scale of one to --
宝·德里克[曾主演电影《10》]
Bo Derek!
10 我知道了
10. Got it.
那分数倒是一点都没错啊
Boy, they did not get that score wrong, huh?
很好
Good.
好吧 是很好 但好到让人惊艳吗
Okay, it's good, but is it wow?
我们只是要请八个人来吃早午餐
We're inviting eight people over for brunch
邀请信上写了"朋友 罗马人 饥饿的人"
with an invitation that reads, "Friends, Romans, Hungreymen" --
他们会被惊艳到的
they're gonna say wow.
歌洛莉亚
Hey, Gloria.
我在送菲尔去医院
I am taking Phil to the hospital!
什么 他们在送菲尔去医院
What? They're taking Phil to the hospital.
只是胃不舒服
It's just a stomach issue.
麻烦你们去足球队接乔 然后到那边找我们
Please pick up Joe at soccer and meet us over there.
当然 那莉莉怎么办
Of course. Oh, but what about Lily?
那是什么 竖琴声吗
What is that? A harp?
不 天啊 不
No! Dios mío, no!
天使要下凡了
The angels are coming down.
你们还不能带走他
You cannot have him yet!
你好
Hello?
海莉 你能去城市孩童体育馆接一下莉莉吗
Haley, would you mind picking up Lily from City Kidz gym?
我没车
I don't have a car.
艾丽克斯说她在约会 但是她可以去接莉莉
Alex said she's on a date, but she can grab Lily.
糟糕 我们没时间等人去取车了
Oh, crap. We don't have time for this valet stuff.
我不管了
I'm going rogue.
卢克 这玩意儿太慢了
Luke, this thing's not fast enough.
抓一支9号铁杆 看能不能勾到别人保险杠上
Grab a nine-iron, try to hook a bumper.
米奇尔舅舅 我现在有点忙
Hey, Uncle Mitchell, I'm kinda busy right now.
是吗 我马上过去
He is? I'm on my way.
抱歉 孩子们 今天不能多待了
Sorry, boys, gotta cut it short today.
快点快点 快带他进去
Hurry, hurry! Take him!
如果菲尔死了 克莱尔会再找一个老公吗
If Phil dies, would Claire get a new husband?
他不会死的 小家伙
Okay, he's not gonna die, bud.
但回答你的问题 是的 应该会
But to answer your question, yes, probably.
生活还得继续
You have to move on with life.
等等我们
Wait for us.
快让开 快让开
Comin' in hot! Comin' in hot!
你们就停在这里吗
You're just gonna park that right there?
我给这里的外科主任做过衣柜
I did the closets for head of surgery here.
没人敢动我
I'm untouchable.
菲尔 亲爱的 你还好吗
Phil, honey, how are you?
又回医院了
Oh, back in the hospital. ?Oh.
但好多了 因为有艾尔希和她的朋友"静滴"
But better because of Elsie and her friend IV.
如果可以的话 我想请"静滴"来我们家住
If it's okay, I invited IV to come live with us.
我给你带了点东西
Well, I brought you something
会让你感觉好很多
that's gonna make you feel so much better.
手术熊
Oh, Surgery Bear.
我们约会的第一年 一起去了一个园游会
Our first year dating, we went to a carnival.
在玩投掷牛奶罐的游戏时
At the milk-can toss,
有一只克莱尔非常喜欢的熊
there was a bear that Claire really liked.
我花了一晚上想要赢下来 但就是不行
I spent all night trying to win it, but I just couldn't.
隔天晚上又去时 园游会去下个城市了
Came back the next night and the carnival had left town.
所以我开车去到夫勒斯诺市 又失败了
So, I drove to Fresno, failed again.
萨克拉门托 还是不行
Sacramento, no dice.
六周后 在内华达卡森城 总算赢下来了
Six weeks later, in Carson City, Nevada, it happened.
是啊
Yeah.
我给她的时候 看到了她脸上的笑容
When I handed it to her and saw the smile on her face,
我当即向她求婚
I proposed to her on the spot.
总之 从那之后
Anyhoo, it's come with me
我每次住院这只熊都会陪伴我 来祈求好运
to every visit in the hospital since for good luck.
我好担心我给忘了
And I was so worried about forgetting it
所以你猜我做了什么
that guess what I did?
你带上了吗
Remembered it?
我给你带了非常舒服的护颈枕
Well, I brought you your nice, comfy neck pillow,
然后我马上回家给你拿手术熊好吗
and I'm gonna run right home and get you Surgery Bear, okay?
-好的 -好
- Okay. ?- Okay.
-老爸 -对了 亲爱的
- Dad! ?- Hi. Oh, honey.
-怎么了 -为防有三长两短
- Yeah? ?- Just in case,
我给你和孩子们做了一支告别视频
I made one of my goodbye videos for you and the kids.
我发在老地方了
I posted it in the usual spot.
-好了 -告别视频
- Okay. ?- Goodbye videos?
没什么 别担心
It's nothing, don't worry about it.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back. I'll be right back.
-好啊 菲尔 -嗨
- Hey, Phil. ?- Hi.
你感觉怎么样
How you feeling?
你跟他们说长裤的事了吗
Did you tell them about the long pants?
对 他们得把我的长裤剪掉
Oh, yeah, they had to cut me out of them
因为裤子缠上了
when th-- when they got tangled up
轮椅的辐条
in the spokes of the wheelchair!
医院给了他上好的麻醉药啊
Well, they gave him the good stuff.
很高兴你们赶上了祝他好运
Well, glad you got to wish him well.
我们得让他准备接受胆囊手术了
We have to get this guy prepped for his gallbladder surgery.
意思是要给我刮毛了
That means they're gonna shave me.
我们要担心这句话是他的最后遗言吗
Should we be worried that those could be his last words?
我来处理 菲尔 我们爱你
I got this. Phil, we love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
他们要给我刮毛了
They're gonna shave me.
我们尽力了
Well, we tried.
你确定菲尔会没事吗
So you're sure Phil's gonna be okay?
肯定没事 宝贝 离菲尔去世还早着呢
Absolutely, Pappy. Phil is not gonna die in a long, long time.
我会死吗
Am I going to die?
乔 这是件自然的事
Well, Joe, it's a natural thing that we --
停停停
Bup, bup, bup.
你似乎不会温和处理这个话题
This is not a topic you tend to handle gently.
也不怪你
It's not your fault,
你生活中的许多人都不得善终
but many people in your orbit met with ugly ends.
我来处理吧
I'll handle this.
好吧 我得去拿派对蛋糕
Fine. I have to pick up the party cake.
一个足球形状的球
It's shaped like a soccer ball.
你确定那不会吓到他们吗
You sure that won't scare them?
因为我只见过他们
'Cause the only thing I've seen them do
飞奔躲开足球
with a soccer ball is run from it.
听着 孩子 这是个深奥的问题
Look, kid, that's a deep question,
"我有天会死吗"
"Will I die some day?"
我要直接告诉你答案 不会
And I'm gonna be straight with you about it -- no.
永远不会吗
Never?
过去 人们大概只能活到12岁
A few years back, people would live to be around 12.
现在 依靠科技的力量
Nowadays, what with all the science they're doing,
寿命无极限
sky's the limit.
你应对得当 有天你就会活到200岁
You play your cards right, and someday you'll be 200,
如果你从你老爸这里学到了东西
and if you learn anything from your old man,
你会挽着一个100岁的美女新娘
you'll have a gorgeous 100-year-old bride on your arm.
女人到了180多岁 会开始爱发牢骚
Uh, there will be some squawking from women in their 180s,
但你是个成功人士
but, uh, you're a successful man
你的努力换得了幸福
and you've earned your happiness.
胆囊到底是什么
What is a gallbladder?
是啊 这些你都不需要的器官是怎么回事
Yeah, and what's up with these organs you don't even need?
你可以切掉胆囊 阑尾
You can lose a gallbladder, an appendix,
啥事都没有
and everything's fine.
是啊 就像是丈夫
Yeah, kind of like husbands.
失去一个 就再找一个
You lose one, you just get another.
你早些时候是这样说的
That is what you said earlier.
我怎么会料到我会引火上身的呢
Oh, how did I know that was gonna boomerang back on me?
我提起这事不是为了攻击你
I didn't bring it up to attack you.
我只是想知道
I just wondered...
如果我提前归西 你想过
have you ever thought about who you'd end up with
你要跟谁在一起吗
if, you know, my show closes early?
我宁愿放弃我的右"胆"囊
I would give my right gallbladder
都不要回答这问题
not to answer this question.
拜托 这是个有趣的游戏
Come on, it'll be a fun game.
你不想知道我心里想的是谁吗
Don't you want to know who I'm thinking about?
有点想
I guess.
好吧 那就数到三一起说名字
Okay, well, then, let's just say a name on three.
-小卡 -拜托
- Cam. - No, come on.
我觉得我的选择会让你惊讶
I think you'll be surprised by my choice.
准备好了吗
You ready?
一二三
One, two, three...
-凯莱布 -你是我的一切
- Caleb. - You're my everything.
-你诈我 -凯莱布是谁
- Y-You -- You tricked me. - Okay, who's Caleb?
你见过他 在乔撒姆的派对上
You -- You met him. At -- At Jotham's party.
那个按摩师
The -- The massage therapist.
看来他按摩按到了你心坎儿里
Well, I guess he rubbed you the right way.
小卡 拜托
Cam, oh, come on.
我说了名字只是因为你逼我说
I only said a name because you pressured me to.
我就跟他聊过两次天
I've had like two conversations with him.
我选他只是因为他让我想到了你
Look, I-I only picked him because he reminds me of you.
贴心 坦率 跟我很互补
So sweet and open and such a good balance for me.
我觉得他可能也是
I-I thought he might be, too.
真有爱
Well, then, that's lovely.
谢天谢地 我剪了正确的线[炸弹]
Oh, thank God. I cut the right wire.
胆囊是什么
Okay, what is a gallbladder?
胆囊是
The gallbladder is
"储存胆汁的4英寸梨形器官"
"A 4-inch pear-shaped organ that stores bile."
像是胆汁橱柜
Like -- Like a little bile cabinet.
这就是为什么大家喜欢有我们陪伴
That's why people want us around.
凯莱布
Uh, Caleb.
米奇尔
Hey, Mitchell.
谢谢你这么快就赶来了
Thanks for coming on such short notice.
你可以在电视那边支按摩床
You can set your table up, uh, down in the TV area.
好 没问题
Sounds good. ?You got it.
怎么回事
What's going on?
你能别这么疑神疑鬼吗
Uh, would you stop being so suspicious?
你说拍照摆姿势把你的脖子弄疼了
You said you neck hurt from posing for our photograph...
于是我邀请了凯莱布过来做他的工作
...so I invited Caleb over to ply his trade.
我觉得他不是来工作的
I do not think he's here to ply.
而是方便你"窥探工作"的
I think he's here so you can pry.
爸爸会没事的
Dad's gonna be fine.
既然聊到这事 在我的葬礼上
Since we're on the subject, at my funeral,
记得让抬棺人说这些话
make sure the pallbearers say things like,
"她真轻"
"Wow, she's so light,"
"她是不是没被装在棺材里啊"
and things like, "Is she even in here?"
我不想被埋葬 我要为科学捐献身躯
I don't want to be buried. I'm donating my body to science.
-你已经算捐了吧 -我要在你棺材里放壶铃增重
- Haven't you already? - I'm putting kettle bells in your coffin.
还得确保我的尸体被捐去常春藤联盟大学
And make sure my cadaver goes to an Ivy League.
我可不想让史瓦兹摩尔学院的宿醉新生
I don't want some hungover freshman from Swarthmore
对我上下其手
getting his hands all over me.
也没那么糟糕啊
Mm. It's not so bad.
我不会死的
I'm never gonna die.
随着科学的发展 一切都有治愈办法
Science is gonna find a cure for everything.
外公跟我说的
Grandpa told me that.
快 孩子们 听着 手术熊不在楼上
Quick, kids, hey, listen, Surgery Bear is not upstairs.
知道在哪吗
Any ideas?
对了 爸爸把手术熊给乔了
Oh, right, Dad gave it to Joe
那时候他切除了扁桃体
when he got his tonsils taken out.
你可以在我翻卢克的抽屉之前
You could've told me that
告诉我的
before I looked through Luke's drawers.
-哪个抽屉 -我们回头聊这事
- Which drawer?! - We'll get into that later.
不是吧
Come on!
该死
Damn it.
亲爱的 你找到手术熊了吗
Hey, honey, did you find Surgery Bear?
当然
Uh... yeah, sure did.
它就在这 睁着美丽的蓝色眼睛
He's -- He's right here with his beautiful blue eyes.
我一直以为那是淡褐色的
I always considered them hazel,
但它戴着墨镜 谁知道啊
but who could tell underneath those sunglasses?
墨镜 好吧
Sunglasses. Right.
不如你跟我说说你最喜欢
Why don't you tell me what your favorite thing is
手术熊的哪点吧
about Surgery Bear?
你知道 他正好跟我是北极...
Well, as you know, he's the polar...
与南极般的相反
...opposite of me.
我讨厌冲浪
I mean, I hate surfing.
但是消防员喜欢冲浪也合情合理
But it makes sense that a fireman would love it.
当然了
Yes, of course.
在我心里 他在夏天会去当志愿消防员
In my mind, he's a volunteer fireman during the summer
因为教授的假期很长
because professors have those off.
教授可以...对
Professors have -- Yes.
得挂了 亲爱的
Oh, gotta run, honey.
艾尔希要再给我打一针麻醉了
Elsie's here to give me another shot for the pain.
别省药 艾尔希
Don't be stingy, Elsie.
上次我等了好久才...
Last time, it took forever to fee...
谢天谢地你在
Oh, thank God you're here.
哪一只是手术熊啊
Which one of these is Surgery Bear?
都不是
Neither one.
曼尼上大学时我送给了他
I gave him to Manny when he went to college.
那是克莱尔吗
Was that Claire?
不知道 但我们家钥匙给太多人了
I don't know, but we've given out too many keys.
下面的人小心
Look out below!
你在干什么 你会害死自己的
What are you doing there?! You're gonna kill yourself!
不 我不会的
No, I won't.
爸爸说我可以永生
Dad said I'm gonna live forever.
下来
Come down here.
你就这么告诉他的吗 你疯了吧
Is that what you told him? Are you crazy?
我不想破坏孩子的天真
I didn't want to steal the kid's innocence.
乔 我知道你爸是这么说的
Joe, I know what your father said,
但忘了吧
but forget it.
你这样是会死的
You can die from that.
真的吗
Really?
真的 人常因为各式各样的原因而死
Yes. People die all the time.
这就是为什么你得小心
That's why you have to be careful.
每个人都会死
Everyone dies.
你可能会噎死
You can choke
或者重物会砸在你头上
or something very heavy can fall on top of your head.
有次我听说有个小孩爆炸了
One time, I heard there was a little kid that exploded.
修女说是因为他有肮脏的想法
The nuns said that it was because of unclean thoughts.
你明白了吗
Do you get all this?
明白 妈妈
Yes, Mommy.
你的朋友们来了 去欢迎人家吧
Those are your friends. Go welcome them.
乔 我带了小蛋糕
Hi, Joe. I brought cupcakes.
还有什么意义啊
What's the point?
-轻重如何 -如果你在桌子底下看
- You okay with the pressure? ?- If you looked under this table,
你会看到我像个小号手一样流口水
you'll see I'm drooling like a trumpeter.
抱歉
Hey, sorry to interrupt.
泡了热茶 做了手工饼干
Made some hot tea and some homemade cookies.
我突然感到
I'm suddenly feeling some
你肩部有些紧张 米奇尔
tension in your shoulder here, Mitchell.
你会像我一样做饭吗 凯莱布
Do you cook, like I do, Caleb, or...?
不 不如过去频繁了
Oh, no. Not as much as I used to.
是吗 可什么都比不上
Oh, yeah, well, nothin' says lovin'
家常美食那么表达爱意啊
like a home-cooked meal.
我知道
I know.
我经营自己的饭店15年了
I had my own restaurant for 15 years.
但失败了 你破产啦
Oh, but it failed and you lost everything?
不 我得从中脱身
No, I had to walk away.
压力太大了
It's such a stressful life.
但我真的好怀念能为某人做饭
But I do miss having someone to cook for.
小卡 为啥不等凯莱布
Cam, maybe you want to get into these topics
给你按摩时再聊这些话题
with Caleb during your massage?
好 我不打扰你们了
Oh, yeah, okay. I'll leave you guys.
紧绷的肌肉放松下来了
And the knots are melting away.
-我是个鼓手 -这里又好大一块紧绷了
- You know, I'm a drummer. - Big one coming back here now.
你懂音乐不 凯莱布
Are you musical in any way, Caleb?
懂啊 实际上我曾经玩过乐队
Yeah, I was actually in a band once.
但失败了 你失去一切了
But it failed and you lost everything?
不 实际上我们还去欧洲巡回演出几年
Uh, no. We actually toured Europe for a couple years.
我还用那收入买了房子和夏威夷的小屋
Bought me a house and a cabin in Hawaii.
你说夏威夷
When you say Hawaii,
你说的是夏威夷岛吗
you mean the big island of Ha-va-ee?
不好意思 凯莱布
I'm sorry, Caleb.
我刚想起来我得和卡梅隆
I just remembered I need to talk to Cameron
聊下回收垃圾箱的事儿
about the recycling bin.
能让我们单独聊会儿吗
Would you excuse us?
当然
Sure.
谢谢
Thanks.
你不要发神经
You're acting crazy.
好吧 你知道吗
Okay, you know what?
是因为我担心我有健康问题 米奇尔
I have some health issues on my mind, Mitchell,
而且我只是简单地测试一下他
and I was simply evaluating the man
他可能有天会是莉莉的继父呢
who might become Lily's stepfather someday.
小卡 你的健康没问题
Cam, your -- your health is fine.
这可不好说 菲尔今早起床时
You don't know that. Phil probably thought the same thing
可能也这么想呢
when he woke up this morning.
疾病都是潜伏的
Okay. Things lurk.
好吧 原来是这么回事
Okay, so that's what this is?
你 看到菲尔那样你受刺激了
You -- Seeing Phil flipped you out,
但没有潜伏的疾病啦
but nothing is lurking.
好吧 可能我是疯了
Okay. Maybe I'm being crazy.
我让他回去
How about if I send him home...
我亲自给你按摩 怎么样
and finish this little massage myself?
垃圾箱一切还好吧
Hey! Uh, everything okay with the recycling bins?
什么 那个借口啊
What? Oh. Oh. The excuse.
还好 听我说 其实刚才是因为
Y-Y-Yes, and listen, about earlier, um,
米奇尔有点暗恋你 所以我表现得很奇怪
Mitchell has a little crush on you and I was being weird,
但现在没事了
but we're all good now, so...
不 其实很高兴听到这些
No, it's actually really nice to hear.
我刚被甩
I just got dumped...
所以任何的认可我都接受
...so I'll take any validation I can get.
他说了喜欢我什么吗
Did he say what exactly about me he liked?
我觉得是你不粘人吧
I think how not needy you are.
总之我们太对不起你了 你该离开了
Anyway, we've put you through enough, you should go.
我会接着给他按摩
I'll finish the massage.
不用了 不 你们已经付款了
Oh, absolutely not. Please, you've already paid.
而且我走后就得自己待在公寓里
Besides, when I leave, I'm just gonna be alone
和那只我们一起领养的鹦鹉一起
in that apartment with the parrot that we adopted.
西尔维奥在哪 西尔维奥在哪
Where's Silvio? Where's Silvio?
我不知道 他离开了
I don't know. He left!
我突然有种冲动
Hey, I-I just had an impulse.
别按摩了
Let's skip the massage.
我去拿酒 你在卧室里等我
I'll grab some wine and you can meet me in the bedroom.
快 去啊
Go on. Get in there.
走开
Go away!
你都不知道是谁敲的门
You don't even know who it is.
是克莱尔 我需要手术熊
It's Claire. I need Surgery Bear.
时机不对 克莱尔
Not a good time, Claire.
必须得拿到它 老兄
Oh, gotta have it, buddy.
你知道在大学
You know how in college,
每个人都要经历一段反叛期吗
everybody goes through a rebellious phase --
你还记得有次艾丽克斯把自己锁在浴室
You know how one time Alex locked herself in the bathroom
我把门踹开吗
and I kicked the door down?
你紧张兮兮就是为了这个吗 耳钉
That's what all the fuss is about? An earring?
熊呢
Ugh. Where's the bear?
柜子
Closet.
耳钉只是个开始
I started with an earring.
根本没人注意到
No one even noticed.
所以你可能需要升级
So, you might need to up your game, pal.
可以在脖子上绕个蛇
Try wearing a snake around your neck
然后一有人谈论就表现得你很烦
and then act annoyed when people want to talk about it.
抽屉
Drawers?
我采取了不同的方式
I went a different way.
好吧
Oh! Okay.
首先 欢迎来到反叛期
Well, first of all, welcome.
我们这样比较有趣
We do have more fun.
我猜你喜欢这样
I'm guessing you like it,
但你担心其他人的想法
but you're worried what other people will think?
路人甲把我比作网球
A passerby likened me to a tennis ball.
而你不能...
And you can't...
躲在这 等着它长长
hide in here until it grows out.
我算过了
I ran the numbers.
即使是衣物都反过来穿
Even with inside-out wearings,
我也只能宅在这里三周
I'd be out of underwear in three weeks.
好吧
Yeah.
我和你讲讲我认识的最开心的家伙
Um, let me tell you about the happiest guy I know.
他在他家前院拉了一个钢索
He stretched a tightrope across his front yard.
从不在意邻居侧目
Didn't worry about the neighbors.
他用弹簧单高跷跳着去上班
He pogo-sticked to work, and...
关键是 他不在意别人怎么想
The point is, he doesn't care what anybody thinks,
如果他在意
and if he did,
他就得不到那么多的乐趣
he wouldn't have had half the fun he's had.
我再问你
Let me ask you again.
你感觉这头发怎么样
How do you feel about the hair?
还挺喜欢的
Kinda like it. Yeah.
对于杰会讨厌这头发 你有何想法
How do you feel about the fact that Jay's gonna hate it?
我喜欢
I love that.
谢谢了 克莱尔
Thanks, Claire.
我得再抱一会儿
Yeah, I'm gonna hold on just a little longer.
我今天超需要拥抱
I need it today. Okay.
橱柜
Oh. Cabinet.
不是吧
Come on.
抱歉打扰一下
I hate to interrupt,
你就大声嚷说会打回给她吧
but if you just scream you'll call her back,
我觉得你会想先去看乔的派对怎么了
you might want to see how Joe's party's going.
很明显 乔和他的朋友们分享了
Apparently, Joe shared the uplifting news
大家可能随时死掉的振奋人心消息
that his friends could die at any minute.
我喜欢我的工作
Hey, so, I love what I do,
但我以观众的活力为生
but I feed off the energy of my audience.
如果观众没什么热情
And if I'm not getting a lot back,
我就更难忘记我已经45岁
it's harder for me to forget I'm a 45-year-old
科班出身却穿着连裤袜
classically trained actor in a body sock
披风除了当道具 还得当作车厢窗帘用
and a cape that doubles as a curtain in my van.
所以我先走了
So, I'm gonna go.
杰克逊 妈妈来了
Jackson, Mama's here!
你居然对他们说他们都会死
You told them they were all going to die?
不 我只对乔说了 但说的方式很温和
No, only Joe, but in a very nice way.
真的吗 那他们怎么看起来像
Really? Because it looks like the "before" picture
嚼服百忧解之前的对比照片
in an ad for chewable Prozac.
把我们也带走
Take us, too!
乔 过来
Joe, come here.
这件事我们得再谈一次
We need to talk again about the thing.
我只想去床上躺着
I think I'm just gonna go to bed.
等等
Hold on.
我们都会在某天死去不假
It's true we all die sometime.
但像你年纪这么小的人
But someone like you, so young,
会活很久很久的
is gonna live a long, long, long time.
是的 重点是
Yeah, and the thing is,
知道我们会在某天死去是件好事
knowing we're gonna die some day can be a good thing.
因为这能提醒我们
Because it reminds us to appreciate
珍惜我们活着时的每分每秒
every minute that we're around.
这让你很受打击 对吗
It's hitting you hard, isn't it?
我感觉我再也不会笑了
It feels like I'm never going to laugh again.
但这是很自然的
But that's natural.
你面对的是个很成人化的问题
This is a pretty adult thing you're dealing with here.
事实上 如果你接下来几天
In fact, I'd be worried about you if you weren't
没有垂头丧气 我反而会担心
walking underneath a cloud for a few days.
但最终...
And eventually --
你 我 卧室
You, me, bedroom.
我拿了红酒 我想好好红红火火浪一浪
I got the Syrah and I want to do something Syr-wrong.
你不按摩了吗
But what about your massage?
我说了不想按了
I said I didn't want it.
快来
Come on.
米奇尔 我们能这样我真高兴
Mitchell, I am so happy we're doing this.
我们好久没这样随性过了
We haven't done anything spontaneous in forever.
我希望你对我的选择满意
I hope you like what I picked out for us.
和以往比起来水果味更重些
It is a little fruitier than we're used to.
今天可真波折
What a day, huh?
罗马托加袍 看急诊
Togas and health scares...
米奇尔 我爱你
Mitchell, I love you,
我不想让凯莱布夹在我们中间
and I don't want Caleb to get between us.
那你们想让我在哪个位置
Oh, so, where do you want me, then?
我的天 你在这做什么
Wha-? Oh, my God. W-what are you doing here?
我 卡梅隆说你喜欢我
Me? I -- Cameron said that you liked me,
然后你又叫我来卧室等你
and then you said meet you in the bedroom.
你告诉凯莱布我喜欢他吗
You told Caleb that I liked him?
你告诉他来卧室等你吗
You told him to meet you in the bedroom?
我以为是对你说的
I thought I was talking to you.
二位 听起来我们三个都需要放纵一下
Guys, it sounds like all three of us could really use this.
别急 凯莱布
Take it easy, Caleb.
很快米奇尔就是你的人了
You'll have Mitchell to yourself soon enough.
小卡 你命长着呢
Cam, you're not dying!
这我们可不知道
We don't know that I'm not!
我有个表亲就是我这年纪死的
I-I had a cousin that died at my age
死于遗传病
from a genetic condition,
是我妈这边传下来的
and it runs on my mom's side of the family.
如果你有那两种基因就有危险
And if you have those two genes, you're at risk.
所以我今天才神经兮兮的
That's why I've been acting crazy all day.
那就去做个检测
Well, then, take a test
确保你没有那对老妈基因[牛仔裤]
to make sure you don't have that pair of mom genes.
米奇尔 我的确去做了检测
Mitchell, I did take the test.
一周前做的
I took it a week ago,
我太害怕了一直不敢看结果
and I've been too scared to look at the results.
亲爱的 我真抱歉
Oh, honey, I'm-I'm so sorry
你一直都在独自承受这些
you've been going through this by yourself.
我们一起看结果 好不好
Let's look at the results together, okay?
-真的吗 -当然
- Really? - Yeah.
好 我要看了
Okay, here goes.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
你没事
You're okay?
不 是网购订单发货了
No, my Etsy order shipped.
但 好吧 这就是结果
But, okay, here's the -- here it is.
-你来看 我不敢看 -好好好
- You look. I cannot look at it. - Okay, okay, okay.
是阴性的
It's-it's negative.
-什么 -你没事 快看
- What? - You're fine. Look.
-真的吗 -真的
- Is it? ?- Yeah.
我的天 我真不敢相信
Oh, my God! I can't believe it!
这可得好好庆祝一下
Oh, now, that is something to celebrate.
-是啊 我爱你 -我爱你
- Yeah. I love you. - I love you.
好了 伙计们 我不傻
All right, guys, I'm not-I'm not dense here.
我知道我该走人了
I-I know this is my cue to leave.
但你们俩的感情
But what you guys have is...
不是人人都有的
it's very special.
你们该好好珍惜
You should cherish that.
凯莱布
Caleb --
我当然加入
I am so back in.
我只是想说你走时想拿点饼干请自便
I was gonna say, if you want to take the cookies when you leave...
无意冒犯 但你到底看上他什么啊
No offense, but what do you see in him?
不好 我上天堂了
Oh, no. I'm in heaven.
不 你没有 还没有 你活下来了
No. No, you're not. Not yet. You made it.
告诉你一声 手术熊一直都在
And just so you know, Surgery Bear was here
他和医生一起为你做了手术
and scrubbed in for the whole procedure.
那挺危险啊
That's pretty dangerous.
他是妇女研究的博士[医生]
He's a women's studies professor.
再说 我唯一需要的只是我的颈枕
Besides, the only thing I really needed was my neck pillow.
什么
What?
我知道如果不给你找点事让你忙着
I knew if you didn't have something to keep you busy,
你会担心一整天
you'd worry all day.
亲爱的
Aww, honey.
你真了解我
You really do know me.
我真高兴你及时醒过来了
I'm glad you woke up when you did.
你差点错过了一月的第二个周六
You almost slept through the second Saturday in January.
你为什么会这么说这日子
Why would you put it like that?
都听好 都听好
Hear ye, hear ye!
我在此宣布第一届年度邓菲运动会开幕
I hereby declare the opening of the first annual Dunphy Games --
医院特辑
hospital edition.
力量的考验
Tests of strength...
运气...
chance...
-及心计 -赞
- ...and cunning. - Yes!
冠军将赢得令人垂涎的邓菲圣杯
With the winner receiving the coveted Dunphy chalice.
向我们的冠军米奇尔致敬
To our champion, Mitchell!
太棒了
Yes!
熄灭火炬
Extinguish the torch.
第一届邓菲运动会就此落幕
And that concludes the first Dunphy Games.
是冬季邓菲赛
Wi-wi-winter Dunphy Games.
我们七月九日夏季...
We'll see you all again July 9 for the Summer --
见好就收吧 菲尔
Take the win, Phil.
-好吧 -好了好了
- Okay. - Okay. All right.
我们发现老爸这些年来
So we discovered our dad made
拍了一系列视频
a series of videos through the years.
每次他身处险境
Every time he was in danger,
他都给我们拍条告别视频
he made a good-bye video for us.
原来他这个发型已经好久好久没变过了
It turns out he's had the same haircut for a really long time.
孩子们
Hey, kids.
我被困在这间移动厕所里有一阵子了
I've been traped in this portable potty for some time now.
正如你们所见我的小胡子已经弯曲了
As you can see by the curling edges of my moustache,
这里的化学气体太强了
the-the chemical fumes are strong.
我没打算在飞机上度过千禧危机 但
I didn't plan to be on a airplane for Y2K, but...
命运如此
Here I am.
短暂且有爱地告个别
A quick loving good-bye
因为我被一群熊包围了
as I am surrounded by a swarm of bears.
如果我今天有什么不测
If anything happens to me today,
我相信你们三个会永远照顾好彼此的
I have faith knowing the three of you will always have each others.
我的手指都麻了
My fingers're numb.
麻到我都抓不住手机了
To the point which it's hard to even keep a grip on the phone.
不
No!
不 要开始了
Oh, no! It's happening!
要...原来是他们开始放电影了
It's ha- Oh. Ther're-they're just starting a movie.
是动画电影《虫虫危机》
It's-it's "A Bug's Life."
视频都挺傻的
They're goofy.
但他希望临终遗言
But it's sweet that he wanted
是说给家人的 这还挺感动的
his last words on earth be something for his family.
是啊
Yeah.
另外历史进程已经到了
Also, we've reached a point in world history
自拍变得过于简单的时代了
where it's become much to easy to film youself.
没错
Totally.
等等 你在说什么
Wait, what?